本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译创作
最新最快的HR-HDTV 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：spriteNT     小猪儿想妈妈     鬼瞳1540      时间轴：End
校对：小砂锅      监制：可乐嘻嘻      后期：鱼子酱
源  代  码
我采纳了你的意见  很不错  谢了
I took your advice. It was good advice, thank you.
你脸色苍白  没事吧
You're pale, everything ok?
肖恩
Shawn.
Shawn!
听着  我之所以要取消...
Anyway listen I wanted to tell you, only reason why I canceled...
一天给我打三次电话  现在这来电的次数
Oh, he's calling me three times a day. I hear more from him now,
比我们分手前还多  这人有毛病吧
than I did when we were together. What is it with guys?
我提出申请了
I gave notice.
您的车票
Ticket.
什么申请
Notice?
请出示您的车票
May I see your ticket?
我...
I...
今天早上你都有点魂不守舍  没事吧
You are acting a little strange this morning, are you ok?
您的票
Ticket?
-晚点的十分钟能追回来吧  -先生  我们尽量
- Are we gonna make up the ten minute? - We gonna try, Sir.
老头  他妈的怎么晚点了
Hey, grandpa, what the hell was the delay back there?
-我只负责查票  -你真该插自己...
- I just punch the tickets, Sir. - You should punch your face...
肖恩  我做了什么吗
Shawn, did I do something?
听着  我知道
Look, I can see that you
你觉得你认识我  但我不认识你
think you know me but I don't know who you are
我是考尔特・斯蒂文斯上尉
My name is Captain Colter Stevens.
我是驻阿富汗美军的直升机飞行员
I fly helicopter for the US Army in Afghanistan.
-肖恩  这也太...  -肖恩
- Shawn, that's... - Shawn?
我有点恶心
I feel sick.
-我靠  -对不起  我帮你捡
- Dammit! - Sorry! Let me help with that...
没事  不要紧的
No, it's ok.
沃尔特・里德  部队医疗中心
先生  等下
Hey mister! Hey!
-你把这落下了  -谢谢
- Hey, you dropped this! - Thanks!
-这是哪  -芝加哥
- What is that? - Chicago.
车门即将关闭  请全员上车
All aboard. Doors are closing.
本车是芝加哥城郊往返列
This is a Chicago-down train.
你没事吧  上尉先生
You ok there, Captain?
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
你真把我吓到了
You kinda freaking me out.
不不不不不不不...
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no...
西恩・芬特雷斯  教师
-你没事吧  -我不知道到底怎么回事
- Are you alright? - I don't know, what's going on...
-肖恩  跟我说说  -听着  我不知道谁是肖恩
- Talk to me Shawn! - Look, I don't know who Shawn is,
我也不认识你
and I don't know who you are!
这样  我们下站下车
Ok, we get off at the next stop
就当什么也没发生过  好吗
and forget whatever is going on here, ok?
这压根不是我的
This doesn't belong to me.
看着我  一切都会好起来的
Look at me, everything is gonna be ok!
考尔特・斯蒂文斯上尉  这是围城
Captain Colter Stevens, this is Beleaguered Castle.
考尔特・斯蒂文斯上尉
Captain Colter Stevens,
这是围城  请确认通信
this is Beleaguered Castle, acknowledge transmission.
斯蒂文斯上尉  收到了吗
Captain Stevens, do you copy?
我这是在哪
Where am I?
你正在"围城"中  你还好吗
You are with "Beleaguered Castle." Are you functional?
头晕  我是不是被锁住了
I am dizzy. Did I... Did I just a-lock?
现在调整你的朝向
Adjusting your rotation.
你这次能报告了吗
Can you report this time?
这他妈是什么鬼东西
Fuck is this? What this is?
你在...我这是跟谁在说话
Where... who I am talking to?
上尉  描述下你刚才的所见所闻
Captain report what you saw.
我听不懂你在说什么
What, I don't understand it.
和我说话前  你在哪
Where were you before you were talking to me?
-那里发生了爆炸  -哪里
- There was an explosion. - Coming from where?
在这个阶段意识有点模糊很正常  上尉
Some confusion is perfectly normal at this stage, Captain.
能看到画面吗
Do you have a visual signal?
你是谁
Who are you?
-你知道我是谁  -知道吗
- You already have that information, Captain. - I do?
说出我的名字
Recall my name.
我们将重建片段  请集中注意力
We'll rebuild the pattern. Try to focus.
我...在执行任务
I... was on a mission.
在开飞机
I was flying...
醒来之后就在一辆火车上
And then I woke up on a train.
现在又到这了
Now I am here.
你得跟我说清楚
I need to be briefed.
你说这是什么部队来着
Uhm, wha-what unit is this?
-围城  -谁
- You're with Beleaguered Castle. - Who?
准备启动阿尔法记忆片段一号线程
Stand by for thread 1 of alpha memory pattern.
"围城"是什么
What is "Beleaguered castle?"
这些题目将对你有所帮助
The exercises will assist you.
一号记忆线程  请听下面的段落
Memory thread 1. Listen to the following passage.
莉莉醒来时穿着晚礼服  披着夜礼服斗蓬
Lilly awoke in an evening dress and an opera cloak...
她手中拿着五张牌
...in her hand were 5 play cards.
你在讲笑话吗
Is this a joke?
黑桃Q  梅花四
The Queen of Spades, Four of Clubs...
梅花九  红桃三  红桃九
...Nine of Clubs, Three of Hearts, Nine of Hearts.
这是红旗军事训练吗[内利斯空军基地的训练]
Is this a red flag exercise?
一号线程终了  开始二号线程
End of thread 1. Thread 2:
下面是鸣角^的叫声记录
The following is a recording of a western screech-owl.
二号线程终了  片段完毕  请确认
End of thread 2. End of pattern. Acknowledge.
确认片段终了
Acknowledge end of pattern.
准备好进入片段回想了吗
Stand by to initiate pattern recall?
启动片段回想
Go for pattern recall.
不考虑牌色
Arrange the 5 playing cards
降序重新排列这五张牌
in order of descending value irrespective of the suit.
-Q  两张九  四和三  -回答正确
- Queen, two nines, four and a three - That is correct.
我读的段落
The passage I read contained
提到一个女人的名字  她叫什么
mention of a woman's name. What was that name?
莉莉
Her name is Lilly.
正确  说出我的名字
That's correct. Recall my name.
戈德温  你叫戈德温
Goodwin, your name is Goodwin...
正确  上尉  欢迎回来
That is correct. Welcome back, Captain.
女士  我要和我父亲说话
Ma'm, I need to talk to my father.
有人得知我回到美国了吗
Has anybody been notified that I am stateside?
上尉  列车是谁炸的
Who bombed the train, Captain?
-什么  -列车是谁炸的
- What? - Who bombed the train?
那个一直叫我"肖恩"的女人.
A woman kept calling me "Shawn".
那只是场邂逅  好好回想  上尉
That is incidental. Think Captain, remember back.
列车是谁炸的
Who bombed the train?
我他妈怎么知道是谁炸了那列车
I don't know who bombed the god damned train.
-那就回去再试一次  -回哪去
- Then go back and try again. - Back where?
和上次一样  你有八分钟
You will have 8 minutes, same as last time.
不  我受够这狗血的模拟测试了
No, no, no, no, no. No more bullshit sim tests, ok?
我得知道  我到底在哪
I need to know, where I am,
我的队友又在哪  他们还好吗
what is the location and condition of my crew.
有人知道我回国了吗
Does anybody know that I am stateside?
你有义务告诉我这些信息
You are obligated to give me this information!
先从炸弹入手
Start with the bomb!
找出它的位置以及外观
Where is it, what does it look like.
-确认它的类型和引爆方式  -得  得
- What kind of explosive, how is it detonated. - Right, right...
先找到炸弹  然后便能锁定安置它的人
Find the bomb and you'll find the bomber.
找到炸弹  等下  不
Find the bomb...Wait nooo!
我采纳了你的意见  很不错  谢了
I took your advice. It was good advice. Thank you.
还行吧
Yeah, it's good.
我选上了NALSAR的课  接下来嘛
And I signed for a NALSAR course. Next thing you know,
NALSAR法律研究的全国学院和法律研究大学
我将移居印度  寻找自我
I'll be moving to India to find myself.
-你还别说  -认识什么不错的大师吗
- Don't say... - Know any good Gurus?
她弄湿了你的鞋
Oh, she got your shoe...
你觉得呢  我算步入正轨了吗
So, what do you think? Am I on the right track?
是同一辆火车  但又有些不同
It's the same train but it's different.
深刻啊  我也希望它与众不同  跟你想的一样
Deep. I hope it's different. I feel the same way.
怎么了
What?
布莱恩打来的  他有毛病啊
Brian... What is it with guys,
把一切留给回忆不是更好吗
everything is more beautiful in retrospect.
看起来如此真实
This looks so real.
我觉得  自己要想过得好
You know, I think it's gonna be really
就得尽可能远离他
good for me to get as far away from him as possible.
-这细节刻画地真赞 -您的车票
- Unbelievable detail. - Ticket.
请出示您的车票
May I see your ticket?
谢谢
Thanks.
他们不会让行动干系人出现在我面前
They wouldn't put the doer in front of me.
行动干系人
The doer?
你很漂亮  你就是那个分心点
You are the pretty girl. The distraction.
-"分心点"  -每次模拟中都有分心点
- "Distraction"? - Every sim has one.
-晚点的十分钟能追回来吧  -先生  我们尽量
- Are we gonna make up the ten minute? - We gonna try, Sir.
- 你是在说布莱恩的事吗  -老头
- Are you talking about Brian? - Hey Grandpa...
他妈的怎么晚点了
What the hell was the delay back there?
-你在赶什么  -什么
- What you late for? - What?
你好像很在意时间  你在赶什么
You seem concerned about the time. What are you late for?
我要赶一个操蛋庆典  你多管什么闲事
I'm late to an asshole festival... I hear you're headlining.
搞笑吧  以为你谁啊  笑星啊
Oh that's funny. Who are you, a comedian?
没错  他就是个喜剧演员
Yeah, he is a... comedian.
坐下  怪胎
Sit down, freak.
可怕的粉丝
Fans...
他你都不认识吗
That's the guy.
美国达人上得了第三  两次因为酒驾入狱
He came in 3rd on America's Got Talent. Got sided twice for DUI.
-我们八卦过他了  -懂了  小姐  谢谢
- We talked about him. - Thank you, ma'm, thank you.
-不客气  -格伦布鲁克站到了
- You are welcome. - "Glenbrook station."
但是一点钟那会儿桥会很堵
Yeah, but at 1 o'clock the bridge is gonna be jammed.
我靠
Damn it!
对不起
Ah, I am sorry.
亲爱的  真有趣
It's funny, honey.
驾照  伊利诺
先生等下  等下
Hey Mr.! Hey!
-你把这落下了  -谢谢
- You dropped this. - Thanks.
车门即将关闭  请全员上车
All aboard, doors are closing.
本车是芝加哥城郊往返列
This is a Chicago-down train.
爆炸是在我后面来的
The explosion came from behind me.
-你是怎么回事  -我现在没空和你聊天
- What's with you? - Out of time to talk to you right now.
我有的是时间
I got time for you.
下一站  终点站芝加哥
The next stop, Chicago, Union Station.
我操
Oh, shit!
戈德温  你会告诉我怎么拆了它吗
Goodwin, you gonna tell me how to disarm this?
我该...拆了它  还是该忽略它
Should I... unplug it? Or do you want me to just leave it?
那我不管了
I am just gonna leave it.
可以吗
Ok?
身份证  西恩・芬特雷斯  教师
乘客们  我是运输安全人员
Ladies and Gentleman, Transit Security.
-是个毛  -由于某项未公开的侵害安全行为
- You're not. - Due to a classified security-breach I need all of
请在进站前
you turn off your personal electronic devices
关闭所有电子设备  好吗
till we pull into the station, ok?
手提  手机统统关闭  请关掉手机  先生
That means laptops, cell phones, cell phone, Sir.
关掉手机  先生  非常感谢
Cell phone, Sir! Thank your very much.
呼机也得关  关掉一切电子产品  谢谢
Pagers, anything electronic. Thank you.
这只是防范措施  无须担心
It's a precautionary measure, it's nothing to worry about.
到底是什么  有安全侵害还是防患于未然
So which is it, security breach or precautionary measure?
先生  关掉
Sir!
先生  你没听明白吗
Is there a problem here, Sir?
这个重要的谈判才到一半
I am in the middle of a very big deal...
肖恩
Shawn?
把那个关掉
I need you to turn that off.
把你的证件再给我瞅眼
Why you don't show me that ID again?
肖恩
Shawn!
关掉
Turn it off!
你有毛病啊  混蛋
What's your problem, asshole?
肖恩  你搞什么鬼
Shawn, what are you doing?
女士  那么做可不妥
Hey, not a good idea m'am.
最好别  最好别打电话哦
Not a good idea. Oh, that's not a good idea.
你把他下巴打断了
I think you broke his jaw.
无妨  他跟你一样  全是幻象
It's ok, he is not any more real than you are.
幻象  你下次自己开车上班去啊
I am not real? How about next time you drive to work!
没有下次了
There's not gonna be a next time.
稳住
Stabilize.
放慢心跳
Lower your pulse.
-你找到炸弹了吗  -是的
- Did you find the bomb? - Yes...
地上都是液压油
There is hydraulic fluid all over the floor.
无须担心  上尉
It's not a concern, Captain.
-这是  -跟我说说炸弹
- What is... -Tell me about the bomb.
他是谁  在监控里拄根拐杖的男人
Where is that man? I saw a guy with a crutch on the monitor.
貌似他才是老大
He looks like he is in charge,
-我要和他谈谈  -那不可能  上尉
- I wanna talk to him. - That's irrelevant, Captain.
我要跟你的指挥官谈谈
I wanna talk to your commanding officer!
你可以在完成任务之后与他交谈
You can talk to him upon completion of your mission.
我的分队在阿富汗  我在那执行任务
My mission is in Afghanistan, where my unit is.
我他妈昨天飞了两次
I flew two god damn sorties yesterday.
你这两个月都跟我们在一起
You've been with us for 2 months.
-找到设弹人了吗  -没  我的分队在哪里
- Did you id the bomber? - No, where is my unit?
这个模拟实验是谁负责的
And under whose jurisdiction is this simulation?
上尉  这不是模拟实验
Captain, this is not a simulation.
你肩负了无数人的性命
Lives are depending on you.
什么性命
What lives?
关于炸弹  你还记得什么  描述一下引爆器
What do you remember about the bomb? Tell me about the detonator.
等下  什么性命  你在说什么
No, no, no, what lives? What you are talking about?
你得跟我说清楚
I need to be briefed!
-长官  得告诉他点内情  -没事  说吧
- Sir, I need to give him something. - That's fine, go ahead.
准备把他送回去
Get ready to send him back in.
今早  中央标准时间七点四十八分
48 this morning CST, a bomb exploded on a
在芝加哥一辆市郊往返列车上
commuter train outside of Chicago,
一枚炸弹爆炸  无人生还
killing everyone on board.
也就是你所在的那辆列车
And that's the train that you've been on.
不可能  我不在这吗  你正在跟我说话
No, no, no, I am right here, you are talking to me right now!
一名叫肖恩・芬特雷斯的男人在那趟列车上
A man named Shawn Fentress was on that train.
总而言之  他现在就是你了
He, for all intents and purposes, is now you.
每多花一秒钟解释
Every second spent explaining
就会有更多无辜人的性命陷入危险
things puts more innocent civilians at risk.
胡说八道
This makes no sense.
火车爆炸只是一系列袭击的第一波
The train explosion was the first attack of a series.
接下来会有更多
There are going to be more.
你找到炸弹了吗
Now, did you find the bomb?
在厕所里  水槽上方的通风板那
In the restroom, ventilation panel above the sink.
引爆器是手机  行了吗
Cell phone detonator. Are we done?
还没  不过你干得很不错  上尉  做得好
Eh, no no. But that's good, that's very very good, Captain. Good.
数据显示  爆炸时刻
Our record show that 1812
共有1812通电话完成通话
calls ended at the moment of the explosion.
有五十二通电话
52 of those calls
经由离火车最近的信号塔转接
were tethered to the cell tower nearest the train.
其中就有设弹人打的电话
So one of those calls was made by our bomber.
你记不记得爆炸时
Do you remember a freight
正好有辆货运列车经过
train passing by just before the explosion?
记得
Yes.
在爆炸发生的时刻  货车刚好经过
The explosion was timed to engulf the passing freight train
这表明
which means,
设弹人是在可见两车的情况下打的电话
the bomber had to be watching both trains when the call was made.
五十二个人  其中一个是设弹人
52 callers, one of those is our bomber.
我要你留意同车厢的乘客
I want you to concentrate on the passengers in your car.
了解他们  缩小嫌疑人范围
Get to know them, narrow the suspect pool.
留意那些不动声响或孤僻的家伙
Look for ones who seem quiet or withdrawn,
和面露不安的人
who seem nervous.
同样  你只有八分钟
As always, you'll have 8 minutes.
八分钟  然后我又被炸飞
8 minutes, and I blow up again?
是的
Yes.
我要你这次严于律己
I need you to discipline yourself on this next pass.
执行我们指定你做的任务
Perform only the task that we assign you.
其它的都无关紧要
Everything else is irrelevant.
驱动通电
Charge the drivers.
我爸爸...
Is my father even...
我采纳了你的意见  很不错
I took your advice... It was very good advice.
-你今天挺沉默的啊  -烦心事比较多  小心
- You're kinda quiet today. - Just got a lot on my mind. Careful.
-对不起啊  -没事
- Oh, so sorry - Don't worry about it.
你真善良
That's very kind of you.
知书达理
You're very decent.
多谢夸奖
Thank you.
-也很真实  -您的车票
- And real. - Ticket.
-今天还好吗  -不错
- How's everything today? - It's good.
-有没有什么异常 -没有
- Anything out of the ordinary? - Uhmm no.
我是指  车上人的行为
I mean behavior on the train.
有没有...在你看来很诡异的人
Is anything... Anybody seems strange to you?
你就很诡异
You look strange.
你呢  有没有觉得谁比较可疑
How about you, does anybody looks suspicious?
-你是喝醉了还是怎么  -过来  就一会
- Are you drunk or something? - Come here. For a second.
来吧
Come on.
-把它当成一个游戏  -游戏
- Just think of it as a game. - A game?
他们再正常不过了
They are all so utterly normal,
肖恩  这也是他们的可怕之处
Shawn. That's what so terrifying about them.
也许他们暗中是一伙的
Maybe there's a team network.
睡觉的胖子和牧师还有那几人有勾搭
The sleeping giant coached with the minister and them out there.
别忽略掉这个忧郁的大学生  他可是牺牲品
Don't forget the sullen college kid, he is the expendable one.
我打赌  所有人都听命于售票员
I bet they are all controlled by the conductor.
他就站在那里专横地查看车票
Standing there dictatorial demanding tickets.
-你太搞了  -该死的
- You are funny. - Damn it.
-那他呢  -失业中
- What about that guy? - Deposition.
他对面的那女人呢
About that woman sitting across from him?
每周一  她都会去做头发  你不知道吗
Hair appointment, every Monday, you know this.
你跟他们比我跟他们聊的多啊
You talk to this people more than I do.
没错  她后面那男的呢
Right, right. And the guy behind her?
他试镜要迟到了  对吧
He's late for an audition, right?
他可有犯罪记录  被送进过...
To record offenses... That's the guy that was sided...
酒后驾车  我懂  信号咋样
A DUI, I know. Hey, how's the signal in here?
不错
It's good.
平时教书还不够刺激吗  大侦探
Is teaching not stimulating enough for you anymore, Sherlock?
看来我们又遇到种族问题了
Oh oh, now we slip to the racial profiling, that is.
还有别人从厕所出来过吗
Did anyone else come out of the bathroom over there?
-我看到你从里面出来  -我
- Well, I saw you coming out of there. - Me?
-没错 -不可能
- Yes. - No.
真的是我
Me?
等下先生
Hey Mr..
让一下  等一下  就一会儿
Hold on, hold on a second. Just hold on a second.
这附近肯定有什么东西
It's gotta be something near.
一个破手机
A broken phone.
和克莉丝汀娜喝咖啡
-克莉丝汀娜  -怎么了
- Christina? - Yeah?
等下
Excuse me.
-跟我一起下车  -我们还没到站呢
- Hey, hey come with me. - This isn't our stop!
-来吧  去走走  -我们不在这站下
- Now come on, let's take a walk. - We don't get off here.
-我一时性起  -你把我吓到了
- I don't know, just be spontaneous. - You gonna freaking me up...
虽然听起来很怪  但我总觉得
I know this gonna sound really weird but I have a
这趟车会发生什么不幸
really bad feeling about this train
我们该下车  好吗
and I think that we should get off, ok?
把你的东西带上
Just get your stuff.
车门即将关闭  请全员上车
All aboard. Doors are closing.
快点  跟我来
Come on, come with me.
-现在呢  -等下  我马上回来
- So what now? - Wait, one... I'll be right back!
现在可以去喝咖啡了吗
Ready to get that coffee now?
对不起  再等一会  就一会好吗
Oh sorry, yeah, ah... Jus... just one more second, ok?
有完没完
Oh for God's sake.
不舒服吗
Feel sick?
晕动病  一直都有
It's motion sickness, I get it all the time.
坐过去点 过去点
Excuse me... Excuse me.
-你在跟踪我吗  -能用下你的手机吗
- Are you following me? - Can I borrow your phone?
不行  我没有手机
No, I don't have one.
-你肯定  -当然
- Sure? - Yeah, I am sure.
你能不能离我远点  我要报警了
Why you don't leave me alone please? Or I call the police.
用什么打  你说你没有手机
With what? I thought you said you didn't have a phone.
要知道  你没权利...
You know, you have no right...
你干什么  把包还我
What are you doing? Give me my bag back.
你疯了啊
Are you crazy?
他们是谁
Who are they?
-肖恩  -别过来
- Shawn! - Get back!
肖恩  怎么回事
Shawn, what's going on?
肖恩
Shawn!
快停下  肖恩
Stop, Shawn!
-不是你  -你到底有什么毛病啊
- It wasn't you. - What the hell is wrong with you?
-你疯了吗  -不  不  不
- Are you insane? - No! No, no!
-它在哪里  -松开我
- Where is it? - Get away from me!
-它到底在哪里  -离我远点
- Where is it? - Get away from me, please!
肖恩  肖恩  快起来  肖恩
Shawn, Shawn, get up! Shawn!
肖恩  听我说  快起来
Shawn, listen to me, get up!
-肖恩  -把手给我  从铁轨那上来
- Shawn. - Give me your hand, get off the track...
-先生  快点  -肖恩  肖恩  肖恩  快起来
- Mr. C'mon. - Shawn, Shawn, Shawn, get up...
考尔特
Colter.
戈德温  快回答  听到我说话了吗
Goodwin? Come in, do you read me?
斯蒂文斯上尉  这是围城
Captain Stevens, this is Beleaguered Castle,
收了吗  请回答
do you copy? Please respond.
这在结冰  怎么回事
It's freezing here, what's going on.
什么情况
What's that?
他有麻烦了
He is in trouble.
舱内停止供氧了
I think the oxygen just went out.
戈德温
Goodwin?
Goodwin!
想办法联系上他
Find a way to get through to him.
怎么了  发生了什么事
What is it? What's going on?
三层制冷系统也没出现异常
It's not the tertiary cooling either.
继续联系他  看他能不能收到信息
Just keep sending strings out, see if he hooks on to something.
我不清楚里面是个什么情况
It's hard to say exactly what he's going through.
-长官  -拜托
- Sir? - Please.
我们现在也无能为力
It's not a whole lot we can do from here.
要是情况没好转  他还能坚持多久
If nothing changes, how much time does he have?
一会吧
Some...
坚持不了多久
and not long.
莉莉醒来时穿着晚礼服  披着夜礼服斗蓬
Lilly awoke in an evening dress and an opera cloak,
她手上有五张牌
in her hand were 5 playing cards.
分别是红桃Q  梅花4
They were the queen of space, 4 of club.
戈德温  你听得见吗
Goodwin, you out there?
戈德温  谁是戈德温
Goodwin, who is Goodwin.
我是斯蒂文斯上尉  听得见吗
This is Captain Stevens, do you copy?
斯蒂文斯上尉
Captain Stevens?
机舱内停电了
The capsule lost power.
机舱吗  上尉  你在机舱里吗
The capsule? Is that where you are now, Captain, in a capsule?
你难道不知道吗  你是谁
You should know, who are you?
我去叫戈德温上尉  去叫她
Let me get Captain Goodwin, get to it!
是你发明了这玩意儿吧
You invented this thing, right?
-是的  -你是这的主管吗
-I did. - Are you in command here?
是的  你找到设弹人了吗  上尉
I am. Were you able to locate the information we need, Captain?
没能找到 长官
That's a negative Sir. I was unable to find the bomber,
但我救了她  一个火车上的乘客
but I did save her. A passenger on the train.
我让她安全下了车  一个女人
I got her off safely, a woman.
上尉  如果你试图拯救车上的任何一人
Captain, it's gonna be counterproductive for you
系统都将对你产生反作用
to try to save anyone on that train.
他们在你的任务范畴之外
They're outside the mission.
但她逃过了这场爆炸  或许其他人也可以
Well, but she survived. And maybe the rest could too.
她仅仅是在源代码中获救
She survived, but only inside the Source Code.
他们所有人都难逃一死
None of them will be safe.
什么是源代码
What is this Source Code?
这是量子力学寓式微积分
It's quantum mechanics parable calculus.
非常复杂
It's very complicated.
试着跟我解释一下
Try me!
好吧
Fine.
当你关闭电灯  灯泡仍然有余辉
When a light bulb's turned off, there is an afterglow,
这叫延迟光圈效应  你见过吧
a lingering halo-like effect. You seen it?
-是的  -很好
- Yes. - Of course.
我们的大脑也一样
The brain is like that, its electromagnetic
人死后大脑的电磁场仍然处于通电状态
field remains charged, just briefly even after death.
电路依然通畅
Circuits remain open.
大脑还有一个特性
Now there is another peculiarity about the brain.
它存有一个短期记忆轨迹
It contains a short-term memory track
时长约8分钟
that's approximately 8 minutes long
就像便利店的安全摄像机一样
like a convenience store's security camera that
只能在硬盘上记录
only records the last portion of the day's activity
每一天的最后部分
on its hard drive.
把这两种现象结合起来
Now combining these two phenomena,
人死后脑电图保持接通
circuitry that remains viable postmortem and a memory bank
记忆库前调8分钟
that goes back 8 minutes
源代码就能帮助我们利用那重叠部分
Source Code enables us to capitalize on the overlap.
肖恩・芬特雷斯死在了那列火车上
Shawn Fentress died on that train,
在所有乘客中  他是你最好的纽带
of all the passengers aboard he was your best link.
你们在性格  体型  和突触图谱上
You two share the compatibility in terms of gender,
都十分匹配
body size and your synaptic maps.
-那8分钟后会怎么样  -之后  什么都没了
- What happens after the 8 minutes? - After? Nothing.
你将不存在于列车上
You cease to exist on the train.
在源代码中
You cannot exist inside the Source Code,
你无法存在于芬特雷斯记忆的8分钟外
beyond Fentress' 8 minutes.
源代码不是时间穿梭
Source Code is not time travel.
而是对时间的再赋值
Rather, Source Code is time reassignment.
它能让我们进入与现实平行的世界
It gives us access to a parallel reality.
车上人的遇难是个悲剧
Now the deaths on the train were a tragedy
-但是源代码使我们...  -不对  我确实救了...
- but Source Code empowers us... - No, but I saved...
一个人  那个坐在我对面的女人
one person, that girl, that's always
我让她下了车
sitting across from me. I pulled her off the train.
告诉我她的名字
Give me her name.
克莉丝汀娜  我记不得她姓什么了
Christina, I don't remember her last name.
-她叫克莉丝汀娜・沃伦   -没错
- Her name was Christina Warren. - Yes!
-今年28岁  -就是她
- She was 28. - That's her
生于伊利诺斯州莫林市  死于今早的火车爆炸
born in Moline, Illinois. Died this morning on the train.
不对  我让她下了车  她没死
No, no, I pulled her off. She's fine.
-不  她死了  -相信我  她没死
- No, she isn't. - Believe me, she is.
-相信我  -她看见我被一列快车压死了
- Believe me. - She saw me get hit by the express train.
-事情没有任何进展  -不  等等
- This isn't us getting anywhere. - No, no, no, wait,
-等等  -必须把他送回去
- Wait. - We have to send him in.
第二轮爆炸迫在眼前  拉特里奇博士
A second attack is imminent, Dr. Rutledge.
-什么二轮爆炸  -列车的爆炸只是一个开始
- What second attack? - The train was just the beginning.
一系列爆炸的开始
A letter of intent.
抱歉  我听不懂你们在说什么
I am sorry, what are you telling me here?
我们得到消息
We have information that
芝加哥市中心是下一个目标
Downtown Chicago is the next target.
他们准备在市中心引爆放射性炸弹
And they're planning to detonate a dirty bomb.
你知道如此程度的爆炸
You have any idea how many people would die
会使多少人丧命吗
if an explosion of that magnitude were to occur in the city?
说话这会儿  我们已经在疏散人群
We're evacuating as we speak.
我们得在炸弹爆炸之前阻止它  懂吗
We've to stop it before it happens, do you understand?
如果你找到了设弹人  他的第二次爆炸
If you find the bomber, his second attack,
他的真正意图  就能被阻止
the real attack, we think, can be prevented.
我们没时间了
We have very little time left.
爆炸一旦发生就无法挽回了
Out here the clocks only move in one direction.
驱动通电
Charge the drivers.
旁边车厢的二楼
On the upper deck of the next carriage
有一个乘务员室
there is aconductor's compartment.
里面有一个保险箱
It's a small office containing a strongbox.
箱内有一把上膛的手枪  找到它
Inside is a loaded handgun. Get to it.
必要时你可以使用任何武力
You are authorized to use whatever force necessary.
我采纳了你的建议
I took your advice.
很不错的建议
It was very good advice.
-你还在这儿  -当然
- You're still here. - Of course I am.
你猜怎么着
Guess what?
你辞了职  报上了NALSAR的课程
You've quit your job and you enrolled in a NALSAR course.
猜得真准
Good guess.
苏打水罐  咖啡洒了
Soda can. Coffee spill.
听着  别接这电话
Listen to me... Don't answer this.
他配不上你
You deserve better than that guy.
把一切留给回忆不是更好吗
Everything looks more beautiful in retrospect, doesn't it?
你怎么知道...
How did you know there was...
-你对我有多了解  -显然不是很了解
- How well do you know me? - Not that well apparently.
那我们有没有熟到
Do you know me well enough, that if I did something
如果我做了些不合常理
that looked a little strange and was maybe
甚至有点危险的事情
even a little bit dangerous
然后叫你无论如何都要相信我  你会信吗
and told you to trust me anyway, that you could do that?
不会
No.
真是大实话
Wow, that was honest.
你漂亮  善良
You are beautiful, you're kind,
也有着令人神伤的坦率
and you are painfully honest.
你是谁
Who are you and what did
你对肖恩・芬特雷斯做了什么
you do with Shawn Fentress?
这是全新的我
It's the new me.
您的车票
Ticket?
我不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you.
我不会坐回去
No I am not gonna sit in my seat, alright?
他在流血  需要救治
He is bleeding, he needs medical attention.
你想从火车保险箱里面偷枪
Is it true that you tried
这是真的吗
to steal a gun out of the train security box?
小心点  女士
Careful ma'm!
-该死  -你疯了吗
- Damm it! - What were you thinking?
-我能借用下你手机吗  -不行
- Can I borrow your phone? - No!
-肖恩  你需要去医院  -求你了
- You need to go to the hospital, Shawn. - Please!
-求你了  -不行  你需要救治
- Please. - No, you need help.
-我能借用下你手机吗  -不行
- Can I borrow your phone? - No!
你借我手机做什么
Why do you want my phone?
要是你只有一分钟可以活了
What would you do if you only
-你会怎么做  -我不知道
- had one minute left to live? - I don't know.
我会打电话给我爸
I would call my dad.
仔细聆听他的声音
I would hear his voice
然后跟他道歉
and I'd tell him I am sorry.
告诉我一切都会没事的
Tell me everything is gonna be ok.
一切都会好起来的
Everything is gonna be ok.
是的  枪在保险箱内
Oh yeah, the gun in the strongbox,
真是个好主意  多谢你了
that was a really great idea. Thanks for that.
-有进展吗  -我能用下电话吗
- Did you make any progress? - Can I get access to a phone?
我要和我父亲通电话
I need to talk to my father.
我待会试下  不骗你
I will try to work on that soon. Yes, I will try.
戈德温  我表现得怎样
Goodwin, how I am doing?
我只是知道自己在这的表现如何
I am just trying to measure my performance here.
你有没有回去过  我比你表现得好吗
Have you ever gotten back in? Am I doing any better than you did?
我们这是在浪费宝贵的时间
No, we're wasting valuable time here.
没有  我只参与过源代码的指挥工作
No, no, I have never been on the other side
我不适合这项任务
of a Source Code mission. I wouldn't be a viable candidate.
为什么  CAOC-N  那是什么
Why not? CAOC-N, what is that?
因为适用范围很窄
Because the specifications are extremely narrow.
什么适用范围
What are they?
上尉  你现在本该已经找到设弹人了
Captain, you should have found the suspect by now.
我们赐予了你如此强大的战略性武器
This tactical advantage, this tremendous tool that we've given you.
别胡思乱想  暴殄天物
Don't squander it thinking.
拿出实际行动来
Do.
请帮我联系我父亲
Please contact my father for me.
船到桥头自然直  上尉
This will stop at some point, Captain.
只要你完成了任务
As soon as you finish the mission.
你表现得真的很好  你能做到的
And you're doing really great. This will end.
安置炸弹的人都需要特定的工具
Whoever planted the bomb had to have equipment of some kind.
像手套  开头顶通风口的螺丝刀
Gloves, a screwdriver to get into the over the head vent,
手电之类的
flashlight, something.
检查下乘客的提袋  背包  公文包等等
Check bags, backpacks, briefcases, anything.
于是...我采纳了你的建议
So... I took your advice.
-很不错的建议  -老头
- It was very good advice. - Hey Grandpa!
-你在干什么  -我只是...
- What are you doing? - I am just...
在回想些事情
trying to remember something.
-那是什么  -军队的臂章
- What is that? - It's a Military patch.
你参过军吗
Were you in the Military?
是我朋友 他在阿富汗服役
A friend of mine was. He was in Afghanistan
然后就消失了  杳无音信
and he disappeared and no one has heard from him since.
你手机可以上网吗
Do you have the Internet on your phone?
不行  必须要用很长的网线
No, it's just connected to
连接到办公室才行
the office by a really long piece of string.
-你能帮我找找这个人的吗  -没问题
- Do you think, you can see what you can find on this guy? - Sure.
他最近一直在我的脑海中浮现
He's been on my mind a lot lately,
他是考尔特・斯蒂文斯上尉
his name is Captain Colter Stevens,
任职于第17空降部队
he is in the 17th Airborne.
你欠我一个人情
Ok, you owe me.
以后请你喝咖啡
I'll buy you a cup of coffee...
要想喝我现在就可以给你买一杯
Why don't I get one for you now.
克莉丝汀娜
Christina!
我最近一直做着一些梦
I've been having these dreams lately...
非常真实的梦
Really vivid...
-你也在我梦中  -真的吗
- and you've been in them. - Really?
不是那种梦
What... oh, no... No that I wouldn't.
我只是
I.. It's just...
我待会儿再打给你  宝贝
I'll call you back in a minute honey.
好的
Yeah.
-临时抱佛脚吗  - 是的
- Cramming? - Yeah.
什么考试
For what?
心理学  今早有个大测验
Psych. And I got a big test this morning,
那我继续看了
so I should get back to it.
我能借支笔吗
Can I borrow a pen?
当然
Yeah, sure.
伙计  这样可不礼貌
Woooh! Hey, that's not cool man!
-伙计  你的包可真乱  -你干什么
- Man... Your bag is a mess. - What you doing man?
跟我的包一样乱
Never find what I am looking for,
想找东西的时候总找不到
just like my bag. Just like my...
-你还是把包还给人家吧  -一边弄你的交易去
- How about you let the guy have his bag back? - Finish your deal!
别多管闲事  不然有你好看
Stay out of this tough guy or doesn't end well for you.
你没权这么做
You can't do that.
什么都没找到  什么都没有
What am I doing? What am I doing here?
我去  妈逼的
Jesus. Dick.
C-o-c-n
C-o-c-n.
沃尔特・里德  部队医疗中心
打扰了  女士  你好
Excuse me, ma', m. How you doing,
早上好  你在沃尔特・里德任职吗
Good morning. You work at Walter Reed?
是的  以前是
Yeah, I used to.
-我是军人  -你是军人吗
- I am in the Military. - You are in the Military?
-是的  -刚才楼下是怎么回事
- Yeah, yeah I am. - What was going on down there?
我们刚才为这个臂章
Oh you know, we were just having a
发生了一点小争执
little bit of an argument actually about, about this patch.
军队就是这样训练你的吗  袭击老百姓
Is that what they train you to do? Assault civilians?
女士  拜托看看这些字母中有没有你熟悉的
Ma'm please. Do any of these letters, they look familiar to you?
你知道N代表什么吗
Do you know what the "N" Stands for?
在空军中  N代表内利斯
It's Air Force and the "N" Stand for Nellis
能借下你手机吗
Can I borrow your phone?
我可以付钱给你
You know what, actually I can pay for it.
不用借  我可以付你钱
I don't even have to borrow, I can pay you for it.
-我有...100块  -我不要你的钱
- I have like 100 dollars... - I don't want your money.
-用完还我  -好的  非常感谢
- Just bring it back. - All right, thank you so much.
快点  快点
Come on, come on, come on, come on...
接线员为您服务
Post operator.
-请接拉特里奇  -请稍等
- Rutledge please. - Please hold.
-请讲  -你告诉他
- Say, please? - You tell him
-考尔特・斯蒂文斯上尉打来的  -请稍等
- Captain Colter Stevens is calling. - Hold the line.
车门即将关闭  请全员上车
All aboard. Doors are closing.
马上接通拉特里奇博士
Dr Rutledge will be on in a moment.
-我有事要跟你说  -我知道  我找到他了
- I have to tell you something. - I know, I found him.
-你朋友  -我找到他了
- Your friend? - I got him.
-他在阿拉斯加的某空军基地  -不  他不在
- An Air Force Base. In Las Vegas. - No, he's not.
-肖恩  他死了  -什么
- He's dead, Shawn. - What?
抱歉  你朋友两个月前执行任务时殉职了
I am sorry. Your friend was killed in action two months ago.
不  你肯定把名字搞错了
No, you must have gotten the name wrong.
考尔特・斯蒂文斯
Colter Stevens,
第17空降部队的直升机飞行员
17th Airborne helicopter pilot,
我查的第一个网站就有
was on the first site I tried.
他父亲叫唐纳德  对吧
His father's name is Donald, right?
这是上周新闻
This is from last week.
唐纳德・斯蒂文斯
Donald Stevens
将与艾伦诺・戈瓦一起
will join host Eleonor Gwah
主持商议他儿子的死
to discuss the death of his son, Army Captain Colter Stevens
陆军上尉考尔特・斯蒂文斯
who died in Afghanistan
二月死于阿富汗
in February
死后被授予了银星
and was honored posthumously with the silver star.
新闻中还提到
Also on the broadcast
斯蒂文斯上尉
will be Army Sergent Rorbert Alvarez,
在卡达汉城外的枪战中
whose life was saved by
救了罗伯特・阿尔瓦雷斯士官一命
Captain Stevens in a firefight just outside of Kandahar.
节哀顺变
I'm sorry.
上尉
Captain.
-肖恩  说句话  -上尉
- Shawn... talk to me. - Captain.
斯蒂文斯上尉
Captain Stevens,
我是柯琳・戈德温上尉
my name is Captain Colleen Goodwin.
这里是围城  你没事了
You're with operation Beleaguered Castle. You are safe.
告诉我你看见了什么
Now, can you tell me what you see?
-回想一下  -我看见了一张牌
- Just look and think. - I see a card.
很好
That's good.
能听见吗  我们受到了猛烈的火箭弹攻击
Do you copy, we're taking a lot of RPG fire here.
我死了吗
Am I dead?
一个广播节目说一架直升机在乡村坠毁
A radio listing is saying that
我死在里面了
I died in a helicopter crash in country,
我父亲替我接受了勋章
and my father received a medal for me.
你的情况与此任务无关
Your condition is not the issue here
你应该尽力阻止接下来的爆炸
You need to focus on preventing any subsequent attacks.
其他的都无关紧要
Everything else is irrelevant.
新闻说我死了  这无关紧要吗
News report saying that I am dead is irrelevant?
在火车设弹人
Until the person or persons
被抓到之前  是的
who blew up that train are in custody... yes!
戈德温
Goodwin.
将心比心  我是死了吗
One soldier to another. Am I dead?
你大脑的一部分仍在运作
Part of your brain remains activated.
那我身体的其它部分呢
What about the rest of me?
我的手脚仍然可以动
I can see my hands and my feet. They still move.
它们只是表象
They're a manifestation.
是你的主观想象
They're just your way of making sense of all this.
你是说  这一切都是我的想象吗
So..What are you saying? Are you saying that I am imagining this?
我想象...自己仍然
I'm imagining that ...I am still alive,
活在这机舱里吗
that I am in this capsule?
第四安培数下降
We have fourth amp dropping.
上尉  里面怎么了
Captain, what just happened?
能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
这个机舱也只是个表象
The capsule is a manifestation as well.
-我在哪儿  -这是机密
- Where am I? - That's classified.
操你妈的
Fuck you!
上尉  我不能体会你现在的心情
Captain, I can not imagine what you must be feeling right now,
但我们必须马上
but if are to prevent a second attack,
送你回去阻止第二场爆炸
we need to send you back immediately.
上尉  你在源代码中时
And Captain, you cannot deviate from the mission
不能分心想任务以外的事情  甚至...
while inside the Source Code. Even to investigate your...
不能去深究自己发生了什么事
Even to investigate what happened to you.
这个终端的程序一致连续  由不得你乱搅和
There is only one continuum on this end and it can't be unsettled.
我刚还真就搅和了  我从车上给你打电话了
Well, you know, I did unsettle it. I called you from the train.
就在爆炸之前
Just before the explosion,
今早7点46分  他们呼叫了你...
so 7:46 this morning they paged you with a call...
你可能在火车上给我打了电话
You may have made that call from the train,
但我在这收不到
but I would never receive it here.
这是不同的世界  上尉
It's a different reality, Captain.
就算电话接通了
If the call even went through it would be
接电话的也是一个完全不同的我
received by a different me entirely.
这你听起来可能很费解
This may be difficult for you to hear,
但你就是时钟上的指针
but you are a hand on a clock, understand?
我们给你上了发条  你就开始转动
We set you, you move forward.
再上一次发条  你又开始转动
We reset you, you move again.
你的作用就体现在此
And that represents the entirety of your function here.
下次我要给你寄个披萨
You know what, next time, I'll send you a pizza.
我倒要看看  这有没有用
I see, if that makes an impression.
你无法在源代码中
You cannot alter the continuum
改变现实的连续性
of this reality from within the Source Code.
你弄的这玩意肯定是违法的
This can't be legal what you are doing.
实际上
In fact,
你大脑的使用权和整个项目
your acquisition by this program as well as the program itself,
都通过了军事法庭的审核
has been reviewed and sanctioned by a military court.
许多士兵都会认为
You know, many soldiers would
执行这任务比死了要好
find this preferable to death.
因为有机会继续为国家效力
The opportunity to continue serving their country.
长官
Have you...
你到底经历过真刀真枪的战斗吗
Have you spent much time in battle, sir?
这无关紧要
That's immaterial.
我的战友们都会认为
Any soldier I've ever served with
为国效力  死一次就够了
could say that one death is service enough.
好吧  只要你完成了任务  我就答应你的要求
Fine, you can have that in return for completing this mission.
-什么要求  -给你你想要的
- Wha... Have what? - I'll give you what you want...
终结你的服役  让你安息
Terminate your service, let you die.
浪费太多时间了
This is taking too long,
你对他太仁慈  现在起不许休息了
you've been to easy on him. No more rest periods.
我相信  我们会找到跟你受过类似伤
I am certain, we can find other service men with wounds
但却把执行此任务
similar to yours who'll
视为无上荣耀的士兵
consider being a part of this program an honor.
不不  等等  什么
No, no, no, no, no. Wait, wait. What?
送他回去  驱动通电
Send him back. Charge the drivers.
斯蒂文斯上尉
And Captain Stevens,
我得提醒你 这可不只是为了你自己
I'd like you to remember that it's not only about you,
更是为了外面两千万美国人
but it's also about 2 million real world Americans.
你可能不珍惜你的命
Now you may not value your own life,
但我请你珍惜他们的生命
I do however ask that you value theirs.
建议
Advice...
老头
Hey Grandpa...
冷静下来  你回来了
Calm yourself, you're back.
找到设弹人了吗
Did you find the bomber?
车上有几百个人
There... are hundreds of people on that train.
那就一个一个地去检查
Well, then check them out one by one.
你怎样对他们都无所谓  反正他们都死了
Doesn't matter what you do to them, they're already dead.
有必要的话  就拿枪杀了他们
Get to that gun and shoot them all if you have to,
但是一定要搞到有用的情报
but get us some usable intel.
不  等等
No! No, wait!
在找到设弹人之前  你必须反复穿越
We have to keep doing this, until you find the bomber.
拜托  我一直在努力
Please, I am trying, I am trying
谁是投弹人
Who is the bomber?
我在努力
I am trying.
抱歉  上尉  我知道你很累
I am sorry, Captain. I know you are exhausted
我们也都很沮丧  但我们输不起
and we are all frustrated, but we can not fail.
你做得到的
You can do this.
-我做不到  -你可以
- I can't, I can't. - Yes, you can.
你天生就是英雄  即使你父亲也这样想
You are a born hero, son. Even your father thinks so.
你最擅长的就是救人于危难之中
Saving people is what you do best.
我们之前有些矛盾  我不想和他修复关系
It was about a stir, too. I didn't wanna regroup back.
我只是开始觉得
I just... started feeling
他再也不想回家了
like he didn't wanna come home anymore.
-爸  是你吗  -他还是没能回来
- Dad? - Somehow, he couldn't come home.
也不愿意跟我沟通  或是听我说话
and he wouldn't talk to me... wouldn't hear me.
他只说...他不能就这样
Hardly said he just... couldn't
离开他的部队  所以一直在服役
leave his unit out there without him and that was that.
那些战友  才是他的家人
Those guys... were his family.
我说了两件我不该说的事  也许吧
I said two things I shouldn't have. I don't know.
我从未真正了解过他
I never fully understood him.
也不敢相信他就这样死了
And I can't believe he is gone.
送我回去
Send me back in.
拜托别再把我炸飞了
Please don't blow me up again.
拨号  065-012-6758
我知道是你
Hello? I know, it's you.
我会找到你的  给我回头
I am gonna find you. Turn around?
-你好啊  -我吗
- Hey there. - Me?
你惊讶个什么
Why you look so surprised?
坐着别动
Don't.
坐边上点  快  把包放那儿
Move. Move. Move. The bag over there.
往里点  把包放对面然后往里坐
Move over, put the bag over there and move over.
坐过去  把手机给我
Move over. Now hand me your phone.
-这下你玩完了  -什么
- You're done! You're done. - What?
-你不能再害人了  -什么  我不明白
- You can't kill anybody anymore. - What? I don't understand.
-你要用手机引爆炸弹  -什么
- You gonna trigger the bomb with your phone. - What?
我发誓我不知道你在说什么
I swear I don't know what you're talking about.
听着  我叫乔治・特洛克山  是个软件工程师
Listen, my name is George Troxel, I am software engineer, ok?
刚在跟老婆打电话
I was talking to my wife.
再打一次  你再拨一次
Try it again. Your call, dial it again.
那好  我只要按下重播键
Ok, I am gonna press redial.
你的电话就会响  然后我就一枪解决你
Your phone is gonna ring and then I gonna shot you.
该死  很抱歉
Shit, I am sorry. Sorry.
你的东西掉了
Hey! You dropped this.
谢谢
Wow, thanks.
车门即将关闭  请全员上车
All aboard. Doors are closing.
该死  不  开门
Shit, no, no!
不
No!
紧急出口
你可以的
Come on!
停车
Stop the train!
伊利诺斯  5CGY847
-德里克・弗罗斯特  -什么事
- Derek Frost - Yes?
-瞧瞧这个  -干啥
- See this? - Yes?
-眼熟吗  -没见过
- Recognize it? - No.
-上帝啊  -把钱包给我
- Jesus. - How about you give me your wallet?
好的
Ok.
别摸了  你故意落在火车上了
No, you left it on the train deliberately.
我肯定是...不小心掉的
I... must dropped it.
不  你是故意的
No, you planted it there,
这样别人就会以为你死了
so everybody would think you were dead.
-我知道是你干的  -你怎么什么都知道
- I know, it's you. - How do you know so much?
这他妈是什么
Hell is that thing?
给我悠着点
Wow, wow, wow. Wow, wow. Slow down, slow down.
-你想看看吗  -挺爱国的嘛
- Do you wanna see it? - Very patriotic...
动作慢点
Slowly, slowly!
好了好了  退后  退后
All right, all right. Back up, back up! Back up!
不是人人都做得出来的
Not many people could build that.
好吧  你下一个目标是什么
Alright, where is your next target?
肖恩
Shawn?
我的天啊
Oh my god.
肖恩・芬特雷斯
Shawn Fentress.
老师  教历史的
Teacher. History.
我不认识你
I don't know you.
我好像把你女朋友杀了
I think I killed your girlfriend.
为什么
Why?
你把我的计划搞乱了
Oh, you messed up my timing.
为什么
Why!?
你是说为什么做这个
Oh, you mean why this.
因为这世界简直是地狱
Because the world is hell.
但我们可以从废墟中创造一个新世界
But we have a chance to start over in the rubble
前提是  先把它夷为平地
but first there has to be rubble
你是老师  你会明白的
You are teacher. You... will understand.
克莉丝汀娜  挺住
Christina... Stay with me!
挺住
Stay with me!
一切都会好起来的
Everything is gonna be ok.
一切还没有结束
This isn't the end.
那儿检查一遍  我查这边
Check through there I'll go check this way.
这里是围城
This is Beleaguered Castle.
上尉  这里是围城  请确认通信
Captain, this is Beleaguered Castle. Acknowledge transmission.
斯蒂文斯上尉  这里是围城
Captain Stevens, this is Beleaguered Castle,
请确认通信
acknowledge transmission.
我找到设弹人了  我知道他名字了
I have your bomber, I have his name.
你有他名字了吗
You have the bomber's name?
德里克・弗罗斯特
Derek Frost.
他在格伦布鲁克站停车场
He got into a rented white
钻进了一辆租来的白色货车
van in the Glenbrook Station parking lot.
伊利诺斯牌照  5CGY847
Illinois plate, 5CGY847
好  我们行动
All right, let's move.
对了  戈德温  等等
And Goodwin... and Goodwin,
车里还有一个放射性装置
there is a radioactive device in the van
某种炸弹
some kind of bomb.
- 谢谢  上尉  -不谢  女士
- Thank you, Captain. - Yes, Ma'm
谢谢  上尉
Thank you, Captain.
-你的任务完成了  -之前说好的呢
- You now off the clock. - About our deal?
我希望你能站在这个项目的立场上
I had hoped that you might reconsider that
重新考虑一下
for the sake of the program.
考虑过了  我现在想要点别的
I have, I want something else now.
好啊
Good.
我还是想死  但我想
I... I still wanna die, but I wanna
先回去  救下车上人的性命
go back in and I wanna save all those people on that train first.
那不会有用的
It doesn't work that way,
-没用的  -我知道  我都知道
- It can't. - No, I know, I know, I know...
我不指望你相信我  先生
I am not really asking to believe me, sir.
我只是...向您请求这样一个机会
I am just..I am asking to have the decency to let me try.
CPD2  这里是AS11
CPD2 this is AS11
货车已驶近沼泽角  正驶向采石场  完毕
Van is approaching fens cape to the quarry, over.
收到  AS11  我们正前往采石场
Roger that, AS11. We're on the vehicle, that into the quarry road.
我们将在半路实施拦截  完毕
We'll stop him about half way down, over.
AU-SWAT2  这是CPD2
AU-SWAT2, this is CPD2,
封锁这条路的东面出口  完毕
block the east end of the road, over.
AU-Swat2  收到
AU-Swat2, roger that.
我们现在切换到
We are going to switch now
来自芝加哥的现场报道
to a live feed from our Chicago affiliate.
特种部队已逼近白色货车
The swat team is approaching the white van.
今天上午  警方锁定了一名伊利诺斯男子
An Illinois man has been sorted through this morning...
车门...车门开了
The door is op... the door is open and
嫌疑犯被制伏  目前看来他已投降
the man is on the ground. It appears he has surrendered.
今天早些时候  警察在他后院的棚屋里
Earlier today the police discovered a...
-祝贺你  上尉  -发现了一个实验室
- Congratulations, Captain. - ...lab in the backyard shack..
近几个月  弗罗斯特开始在
In recent months Frost started
个人网站上发表反政府言论
posting anti-government statements on his website.
好的  这是对整个项目的认可
Yes Sir, it's a real validation of the program
充分展示了源代码的革命性意义
a clear window into just how revolutionary Source Code can be.
我们终于掌握了反恐的致命武器
We finally have a powerful weapon now in the war on terror.
祝贺你  上尉  干得漂亮
Congratulations Captain, job well done.
他不准备把我再送回去了吧  戈德温
He is not gonna send me back in, is he, Goodwin?
我还在等回复
I am still waiting an answer.
上尉  你结婚了吗
Are you married, Captain?
杰夫  休息一下吧  你该好好庆祝庆祝
Jeff, why don't you go take a break? You deserve to celebrate.
当然
Sure.
-要给你带点什么吗  -不  不用了
- Can I get you something? - No, I am fine.
为什么问这个  想约我吗
Why, you asking me on a date?
不好意思  无意冒犯
Sorry, poor taste.
你结婚了吗
Are you married?
没有
No.
我离了
I am divorced.
你觉得有没有另一个自己
You think there is an alternate version of you?
一个做出不同选择的戈德温
A Goodwin who made different choices?
什么意思
What do you mean?
比如说  你没有结婚
like uh, you didn't get married or
也没离婚  或者刚和别人结了婚
you didn't get divorced, or just married someone else
选择了人生中不同的岔路
a woman who has took a different fork in the road?
不  我不觉得  上尉
No, I don't, Captain.
你所经历的只是幻影
What you experienced was a shadow,
是一个遇害者脑中的残像
it was an afterimage of a victim on a train.
这里才是真实世界
This is real life, here.
跟挂掉的飞行员通话也叫真实吗
The one where you talking to a dead helicopter pilot?
这个程序的初衷不是为了改变过去
The program wasn't designed to alter the past,
而是左右未来  这你已经做到了这点
it was designed to affect the future. And you have done that.
我搞砸了点事情  上尉
I missed something, Captain.
那列车不该爆炸
That train shouldn't have blown up.
肯定还有另一个引爆器
There must have been a second detonator.
备用的  我没发现
Something I couldn't see. A fail-safe.
这是电脑程序  上尉
It's a computer program, Captain.
车上的姑娘  还有其他人  都已经死了
The girl on the train, all the others, they're lost.
我很抱歉
I am sorry about that.
我知道的
I get it. I get it.
量子物理  寓式积分
I know, quantum physics, parable calculus.
但你错了  戈德温  大错特错
You're wrong, Goodwin. You're just plain wrong.
上尉  克莉丝汀娜已经死了
Captain, Christina is dead.
她有机会活下去的
She doesn't have to be, Ma'm.
我问问拉特里奇
I'll ask Rutledge.
我求求你
I'm asking you.
求你...把我...送...
I'm asking you... Just... send me...
送我回去  终止我的生命
只要八分钟而已  戈德温
上尉
Captain.
决定权在你
It's your choice.
这段源代码结束时我会关闭生命维持系统
At the end of this Source Code I'll terminate your life support.
你再也不会回来了
There willl be no coming back.
我一定能拯救她  戈德温
I am gonna save her, Goodwin!
很荣幸为你效劳  上尉
It was an honor, Captain.
谢谢你的表现
And I thank you for your service.
祝你好运
Good luck.
我采纳了你的建议
I took your advice.
你要去印度当老师了
You're gonna move to India and become a Guru.
当心  女士
Careful, ma'm.
没错  我要在深山里找寻自我
Yeah, I am gonna go find myself in the mountains.
走之前  你也许可以跟我喝杯咖啡
Well maybe you have a cup of coffee with me before you go.
好啊  我很想做那个前青春期测试
Yeah, I like to do that pre-teen test.
好的
Good.
要不今天做吧
Let's do it today.
把班翘掉  布莱恩可以找别的助手
Let's just skip work. Bryan can find someone else to assist him.
-你知道吗  -知道什么
- You know what? - What?
我感觉很棒
I feel really good.
为什么
Why?
因为就你这一杯咖啡
Cause I have been waiting for weeks
我都等好几个星期了
for you to ask me for a coffee.
您的票
Ticket.
好的
Ok.
等我几分钟好吗  我马上回来
Just give me a couple of minutes ok? And I'll be right back.
我得去...拯救世界
Gotta go... save the world.
我就知道他是个闷骚子
I knew he was a keeper.
天气真不错
Beautiful day.
-您的票  -不好意思  对不起
- Ticket. - Oh, I am sorry. Sorry.
你相信国防部吗
You trust the DOD?
他们掌管财政大权
They got the finances.
是啊  没错  如果我们拿到资金
Yeah, well sure. Look, if we get the funding.
我向你保证  我们在年底前
I guarantee you... we can have at least...
至少会有八个源代码计划在正常运转
8 Source Code projects up and running by the end of the year.
-真会有那么多吗  -说不定会更多
- Really that many? - Maybe more.
-你真是大英雄  拉特里奇博士  -谢谢
- You're real hero, Dr. Rutledge. - Oh, thank you.
我们今天确实救了不少人
We did save lives today.
是啊  项目大获全胜
Yes, a true victory for the program.
-是我们共同的胜利  -以后再聊
- A great victory for us all. - We'll talk soon.
激动人心的时刻到了
So... exciting times.
启动SC-1记忆移除程序
Let's initialize the memory wipe on SC-1
开始处理数据
and start crunching the data.
先生
...Sir...
我们不是跟斯蒂文斯上尉说好了
We, we... we told Captain Stevens,
让他安息的吗
that we were gonna let him die.
让他死  他刚刚救下了无数条生命
Let him die? He just saved millions of lives today.
有了他  以后能避免多少灾难
How many other disasters might he avert down the line?
而且据我们所知  他可能
For all we know, he may be
是能让这套系统运行的唯一人选
the only candidate with which the system works.
所以  清除他的记忆  初始化源代码
So, let's clear his memory and reinitialize Source Code.
好吗
Shall we?
遵命
Yes, sir.
不好意思  我...
Sorry, I just...
德里克  你不在这站下呀
Hey Derek, this isn't your stop.
先生  你把这个掉了
Hey Mr. You dropped this.
过来  到后面来
Come on, back here.
德里克
Derek.
都结束了
It's over.
明白吗
Do you understand?
我叫德里克・弗罗斯特
Hey, my name is Derek Frost.
我在一辆白色货车中安置了一个核装置
I planted a nuclear device in a white van,
车停在格伦布鲁克站的CCR停车场
parked in a Glenbrook Station CCR parking lot
现在我被铐在944 CCR列车的扶手上
right now I am handcuffed to a pole
列车正驶往芝加哥联合站
on the 944 CCR train, headed to Chicago Union Station.
我是个变态的可怜虫
I am a sick and pathetic human being.
我渴望一段漫长的监狱之旅
And I need to be locked away for a very long time.
好了
Ok.
德里克  今天你是夷不平这个世界了
Derek, there's no more burying the world in rubble today.
不介意我借用一下吧
You mind if I borrow this?
上尉  我们哥几个要去庆祝一下
Captain, some of the guys and I are gonna go celebrate.
他们让我启动记忆清除程序  上尉
And... they want me to initiate the memory wipe, Captain.
你好  上尉
Hello, Captain.
-你好  -是唐纳德・斯蒂文斯吗
- Hello? - Donald Stevens?
是我
Yes.
-我叫肖恩・斯蒂文斯  -你是谁
- My name is Shawn Fentress. - Who?
我和您儿子考尔特一起服役
I served with your son, Colter.
天哪
Oh boy...
很抱歉这么久才打电话给你
It's a... I am sorry it has taken me so long to... call you.
有时候自己需要一些时间
Sometimes it just takes a while
才能找到最想说的话
to figure out what you wanna say, you know.
别太勉强自己
Ah, don't be too hard on yourself...
打这个电话并不容易
It's not an easy call to make.
先生  您过得还好吗
How are you doing, Sir?
运回来的只有些骨灰
All that came back was some ash.
很难相信那就是他
It's hard to believe that it was him.
你有多了解他
How well did you know him?
他牺牲的时候我在场  他说...
I was there when he died, Sir. He said...
你们的最后一次谈话  言辞很激烈...
that the last time that you guys talked, ehm... was tough ...and
他想说声对不起
he wanted to say that he was sorry.
我只想让他平安回来
I just wanted him back.
我很爱他
I loved him so much.
-真希望能亲口告诉他  -他知道的
- I wish I could have told him that. - He knows it.
保重  斯蒂文斯先生
Take care, Mr. Stevens.
-你没事吧  -没事
- You ok? - Yeah.
-拯救世界了  -差不多吧
- Saved the world? - Sorta.
刚说到哪儿了
So, where were we?
去喝咖啡
Getting some coffee.
这是拉特里奇博士
Dr. Rutledge?
什么
What?
该死
Shit!
这有什么难的  我是经商的好吗
What is too hard about it? I run a business, ok?
要么按时完成工作  要么卷铺盖滚蛋
Everything moves on time or people get fired.
现实世界就是这么残酷
That's how it works in the real world.
-十分钟  -老兄
- 10 Minutes. - Hey buddy.
别为些琐事汗流浃背  小心汗水逆流成河
Don't sweat the small stuff, you'll drown.
多谢大师指点迷津
Oh thank you for the moment of Zen,
但我又没跟你说话
but nobody was talking to you.
你算什么  大喇叭广播吗
What do you sound, self help cds today?
管好自己的事得了
Why don't you just mind your own business?
保安  带一队人马过来  速度
Security? Get me a detachment of MPs here. This instant!
为什么你老爱挖苦人呢  马克思
Why are you always so bitter, Max?
朋友  这世界就是如此残酷
It's a bitter world we living my friend.
你想让我怎么办
What you want from me?
没必要这样的
It doesn't have to be.
我赌一百块
I will bet you 100 dollars,
赌你不能把车里所有人逗笑
that you can't make all the people on this train laugh.
好了
Oh right...
这总共有...126块
Actually, 126 bucks.
你就这么玩儿我吗
Is that your way of making fun of me?
不  为了让今天多点欢乐
No, it is to have a better day...
不  我接受  手到擒来
No, no. It's good. Easiest money ever.
打扰一下  朋友们  我的一个乘客朋友
Hey, I... excuse me, people. One of our fellow passengers
给了我点钱
has decided to offer me some money...
你今天怎么了
What has just gotten into you today?
像是变了个人
You're like a different person.
-这是全新的我  -我喜欢
- It's the new me. - I like it.
女人们总把我的姓搞错
Women always mess up my last name.
有天晚上我跟一姑娘在一起
I was with a girl the other night and
她总是叫我"滚开"
she kept calling me "Getoff".
译注: 滚开在英语中与此人姓氏谐音
她说  滚开  滚开  我说  不  我叫丹诺夫
She goes "Get off, get off" "I am "No, Denoff,
她说  不是  你又胖又重  快滚开
Denoff", she: "No, you are fat and you are heavy, get off!"
好了吗  还要二十秒
Good? 20 seconds.
给你十秒
Make it 10.
戈德温
Goodwin.
看看这一切
Look at all this.
什么
What?
所有这些生命
All this life.
戈德温  快把安全门打开
Goodwin, open the SC door!
为什么你总不停看表
Why you keep looking at your watch?
克莉丝汀娜  如果你只有一分钟不到的生命
Christina, what would you do...
你会怎么做
if you knew you had less than a minute to live?
我会让每秒都过得有意义
I'd make those seconds count.
-我会再吻你一次  -你吻过吗
- I'd kiss you again. - Again?
戈德温  把这该死的门打开
Goodwin, open this god damn door!
他已经付出够多了  博士
He has done enough, Dr.
一切都会好起来的
Everything is gonna be ok.
今天是周一  芝加哥的天气很好
It is a beautiful Monday in Chicago today.
最低温度可能会达到60华氏度
Temperature is expected to reach the lower 60.
目前湖上温度为55华氏度
Right now 55 at the Lake...
-他赌赢了  -是啊
- What, he earned that money. - Yea, he did.
他很搞笑的
He is funny.
搞的我现在没钱了
Speaking of which... I have no cash.
过来  我想让你看点东西
Come here, I wanna show you something.
天气真好啊
It's such a beautiful day, isn't it
没错  棒极了
Yeah, it is a really perfect day.
-你相信命运吗  -不太信
- Do you believe in fate? - Not really.
只能撞些狗屎运  过来
I'm more of a dumb luck kind of gal. Come here.
你今天想干什么
So, what do you wanna do today?
我们应该在这多待一会儿
I think we should stay here for a while.
我们命中注定要来这个地方  不是吗
This feels like exactly where we're supposed to be, doesn't it?
-早上好  杰夫  -早上好  上尉
- Good Morning, Jeff. - Good Morning, Captain.
莉莉醒来时穿着晚礼服  披着夜礼服斗蓬
Lilly awoke in an evening dress and an opera cloak.
她手中拿着五张牌
In her hand were 5 playing cards.
今天某个时候
At some point today,
你会得知在芝加哥附近的列车上
you re gonna hear about
有一个作案未遂的恐怖袭击犯
a failed terrorist attack on a commuter train near Chicago.
是我们阻止了炸弹爆炸
You and I kept that bomb from going off.
有人想在芝加哥城外的CCR列车上引发爆炸
An attempted bombing on a CCR train outside Chicago
危险已被解除  在列车上发现了嫌疑犯
but it was foiled. And the suspect was found on board...
名叫德里克・弗罗斯特
Named Derek Frost.
戈德温  有什么事吗
Goodwin, anything I can help you with?
没什么  我一会儿再来
No, that's fine, I'll come back later.
瞪大你的眼睛
Well, keep an eye out.
这几天  总会有危机浮出水面
One of these days, the right crisis is going to rear its head
那时候就该源代码大展身手了
and Source Code is going to have its moment in the sun.
遵命  长官
Yes, Sir.
如果你现在正在读这封邮件
If you re reading this email,
那说明源代码比你和拉特里奇博士
then Source Code works even better than
想的要强大
you and Dr. Rutledge imagined.
你们以为自己在重现过去的8分钟
You thought you were creating 8 minutes of a past event,
但事实并非如此
but you're not.
你们创造了一个新世界
You've created a whole new world.
戈德温  如果我没弄错的话
Goodwin, if I am right...
在源代码设备的某处
Somewhere at the Source Code facility,
有一名在等待执行任务的考尔特・斯蒂文斯上尉
you have a Captain Colter Stevens, waiting to send on a mission.
请一定答应我  你会向他伸出援手
Promise me you'll help him.
那时  也请帮我一个忙
And when you do, do me a favor.
记得告诉他  一切都会好起来的
Tell him, everything is gonna be ok.